# Andrei Tuta

github.com/andreituta linkedin.com/in/andreituta Email: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com

Mobile: +40725565620

Skype: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com

#### Career Profile

A passionate Software Developer with extensive and diversified experience in developing mobile applications, websites, web applications and offering administration services for local businesses.

Knowledge of product-life-cycle management, business development and leading cross-functional teams was gained while managing various other projects and business ideas, focusing on understanding existing and emerging technologies, Software as a Service (SaaS), while minimizing their cost and administering workload.

## EDUCATION

## • Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

B.Sc. in Computer Science - Data Analysis. Machine Learning and Database administration

2015 - 2018

#### • Universidad de Alcala

Alcala de Henares, Spain

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Erasmus semester in Spain

Jan - Jun 2017

#### Professional experience

### • URJ 6 Points Sci-tech

Byfield, MA

Counselor/Specialist

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- Counselor: Camp counselor, tasked with managing and leading daily activities.
- **Programming assistant**: Helping instructors with running the Programming and Coding workshop, focused on teaching programming in Processing for developing their own projects.
- Workshop Instructor: Running my own workshop, in which participants learned the basic syntax of HTML, CSS, JS and the logic behind coding a virtual Monopoly game.

#### • Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Programming assistant

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Java demonstrator: Helped groups of students during their laboratory sessions. Tasks involved explaining concepts and helping with debugging their projects.
- Innovation Fest Mentor: Managed and helped two teams of students with the technical development, planning and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest.

### • Oracle Romania

Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun - Sep 2017

- Oracle DBA training: Part of the internship consisted of a training similar to a complete DBA course. During this training, topics such as basic administration, back-up, recovery and automation were covered
- Administrator: After the training was completed, I completely installed and automated two separate databases to execute all the required procedures.

### Programming Skills

• Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Kotlin, SQL Technologies: AWS, React, Android Studio, MongoDB

#### Extracurricular activities

## • Outward Mobility Ambassador, BCU CEBE

Jan - Jun 2018

Managing, assisting and recruiting students for international programs and social media development

#### • President, BCU RoSoc

2016 - 2018

Event planning, budgeting & team management

### • Secretary, Rotaract Club Birmingham

2015 - 2017

Event planning, PR & note-taking